Guide to the Stanford University. Memorial Church. Records SC.0290
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Memorial Church. records
1893-2004
SC.0290
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
16.5 Linear feet
Stanford University. Memorial Church.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Administrative transfer, Memorial Church.
Historical Note
Following the death of Leland Stanford in 1893, Mrs. Stanford decided to build Stanford Memorial Church as a memorial to her husband. Mrs. Stanford wanted the church to be nondenominational and a place of peace, meditation, and prayer amid the turmoil and tasks of the university.
Construction of Stanford Memorial Church began in 1899. The church was dedicated January 25, 1903. It was partially destroyed by the earthquake in 1906 and was rebuilt and opened again in 1913. The church was again damaged during the Loma Prieta earthquake of 1989 and was closed for repairs until 1993. Stanford Memorial Church is known for its stained-glass windows of the J. & R. Lamb Studios and the masterpieces of its art mosaics created by the Venetian studios of Salviati & Company.
The first pastor of the church was Heber Newton. He preached at Stanford for four months but reluctantly resigned because he disagreed with Mrs. Stanford on some aspects of church management. After Newton's resignation, the trustees of the university engaged the Rev. David Charles Gardner as chaplain of the church. He served thirty-four years, from 1902 to 1936. Gardner was succeeded in 1936 by the Rev. D. Elton Trueblood who resigned in 1945. The Rev. George J. Hall was chaplain from 1946 to 1947 and he was succeeded by the Rev. Robert M. Minto who served from 1947 to 1948 and 1950 to 1973. The Rev. Paul C. Johnston served as chaplain from 1949 to 1950. Robert McAfee Brown was acting Dean from 1972 to 1973. The Rev. R. G. Hammerton-Kelly served from 1973 to 1986, when the Rev. Thomas Ambrogi was named Acting Dean. In 1987, the Rev. Dr. Robert C. Gregg became Dean.
Scope and Content of Collection
The records of Stanford Memorial Church include marriage and baptismal records, church service programs, sermons and lectures, church newsletters and publications, and files from two chaplains.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following nine series:
SERIES I - Church Services (programs), 1903-1973
SERIES II - Sermons and Lectures, 1957-1978
SERIES III - Organ Recitals, 1920-1985
SERIES IV - Chaplains' Records
SERIES V - Baptismal and Marriage Records, 1902-1989
SERIES VI - Bibles, Hymnals, and Songbooks, 1883-1912
SERIES VII - Publications about the Church
SERIES VIII - General Miscellany
SERIES IX - Church Building
When paging materials from this collection, please be sure to include the series number on the paging slip.
Sterling, J. E. Wallace, (John Ewart Wallace), 1906-; Minto, Robert M; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905; Trueblood, Elton, 1900-; Lectures and lecturing; Programs, church.; Sermons.; Church records and registers.; Baptismal records.; Hymns
- Series I: Church Services (Programs), 1903-1973
  - Order of Worship, 1903-1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Order of Worship, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Order of Worship, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Order of Worship, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Order of Worship, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Order of Worship, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Order of Worship, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Order of Worship, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Order of Worship, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Order of Worship, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Order of Worship, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Order of Worship, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Order of Worship, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Order of Worship, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Order of Worship, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Order of Worship, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Baccalaureate Services, 1903-1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Baccalaureate Services, 1955-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Memorial Services, 1933-1936 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Services, 1937-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Holiday Services, 1905-1950 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Holiday Services, 1951-1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Holiday Services, 1962-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Special Services, 1900-1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Special Services, 1951-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Order of Worship, 15 June 1974 - 24 November 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Order of Worship, 1 December 1974 - 28 March 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Order of Worship, 30 March 1975 - 31 August 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Order of Worship, 7 September 1975 - 25 January 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Order of Worship, 1 February 1976 - 25 April 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Order of Worship, 2 May 1976 - 26 September 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Order of Worship, 3 October 1976 - 31 July 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Order of Worship, 7 August 1977 - 17 June 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Order of Worship, 25 June 1978 - 8 April 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Order of Worship, 13 April 1979 - 30 December 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Order of Worship, 6 January 1980 - 28 December 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Order of Worship, 4 January 1981 - 27 December 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Order of Worship, 3 January 1982 - 26 December 1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Order of Worship, 2 January 1983 - 25 December 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Order of Worship, 1 January 1984 - 30 December 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Order of Worship, 6 January 1985 - 29 December 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Order of Worship, 5 January 1986 - 28 December 1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Order of Worship, 4 January 1987 - 27 December 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Order of Worship, 3 January 1988 - 14 August 1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Memorial Services, 1974-1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series II: Sermons and Lectures (Programs), 1957-1978
  - Sermons and Lectures, 1957-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Sept. 1966-May 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Sept. 1967-Nov. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1968-May 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sermons and Lectures, June 1968-July 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Sept. 1968- Nov. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1969- June 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Sept. 1969-Dec. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1970-May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sermons and Lectures, June 1970-Dec. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1971-May 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sermons and Lectures, June 1971-Dec. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1972-Aug. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Sept. 1972-Feb. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Mar. 1973-Aug. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Sept. 1973-Dec. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1974-May 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sermons and Lectures, June 1974-Dec. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1975-June 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sermons and Lectures, July 1975-Dec. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1976-May 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sermons and Lectures, June 1976-Dec. 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1977-May 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sermons and Lectures, June 1977-Dec. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Sermons and Lectures, Jan. 1978-May 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series III: Organ Recitals (Programs), 1920-1967
  - Organ Recitals (Bound), 1920-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Organ Recitals, 1920-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Organ Recitals, 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Organ Recitals, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Organ Recitals, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Organ Recitals, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Organ Recitals, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Organ Recitals, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Organ Recitals, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Organ Recitals, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Organ Recitals, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Organ Recitals, 1955-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Organ Recitals, 1968-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Chaplains' Records, 1936-1965
  - Subseries I: Robert "Rabb" Minto, 1949-1965
    - Minto: Augustinianism (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minto: Autobiographical essay (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minto: Budget, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minto: Calendar, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minto: "The Chaplain," essay and notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minto: Chaplaincy, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minto: Christian faith and university education - lectures (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Minto: Christmas Eve, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Minto: Christmas Services (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Minto: Church School (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minto: Church windows, correspondence and other items (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Minto: The College Church (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Minto: Conference on Religion, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Minto: Correspondence on collections in Memorial Church (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Minto: Easter Services, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Minto: Easter Notes (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Minto: Easter Notes (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Minto: Ecumenical Conversations, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Minto: 50th Anniversary of Memorial Church, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Minto: 50th Anniversary of Memorial Church (correspondence), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Minto: 50th Anniversary of Memorial Church (clippings), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Minto: 50th Anniversary of Memorial Church (programs), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Minto: Funerals (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Minto: Funerals (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Minto: Letters of recommendation, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Minto: Letters received, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Minto: Listing, Stanford Names (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Minto: Liturgy and Architecture - notes and sources (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Minto: Maudy Thursday (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Minto: Medical School, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Minto: Miscellaneous Files (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Minto: Miscellaneous papers, 1947-1954,undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Minto: Miscellaneous papers by others (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Minto: Non-Sectarianism (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1939/40 - 1946/47 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1947/48 - 1949/50 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1950/51 - 1952/53 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1953/54 - 1955/56 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1956/57 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Minto: President's Report, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Minto: Religious Appointments, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Minto: The Report of the LASSU Committee on Religion, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Minto: Requisitions for 1960-1961, Petty Cash Account (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Minto: Sterling, J.E. Wallace, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Minto: Survey of the Religious and Political Attitudes of American College Students (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Minto: Taize, Service and Rules (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Minto: Taize, Prayers, circa 1962 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Minto: Taize, Holy Communion (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Minto: Taize, Essay on (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Minto: Taize, Community of, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Minto: U.S. Christian Council Conference, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Subseries II: D. Elton Trueblood, 1936-1945
    - Trueblood correspondence: Brown, Hugh Elmer; Brown, Wm. Adams; Buttrick, George A.; Cadbury, Wm. W. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Fifield, James; Finnish Relief; Foote, H.W. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Fosdick, Dr.; Gallagher, Euell G.; Gilkey, Charles W.; Griffin, Frederick (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Ham, Roswell G.; Hume, Theodore C.; Hunter, Allan A.; Hunter, Stanley; Japanese Students; Jones, Rufus M. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Kennedy, Gerald; King, Joseph F.; Krumbine, Miles H.; Lester, Muriel; Lewis, William F.; Loofbourow, Leon L. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Lovejoy, A.O.; Lyons, Jesse; McCall, O.W.S.; McGiffert, A.C.; Mackay, John A. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Mathews, Dr. Shailer; Spiegelberg, Friederich; Talbott, E. Guy; White, Lynn T. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Trueblood correspondence: Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Trueblood: Army (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Trueblood: Photographs (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series V: Baptismal and Marriage Records, 1902-1989
  - Baptisms, 1902-1958 and Marriages (Bound), 1903-1937 (Othertype 1)
  - Marriages (Bound), 1938-Aug. 3, 1958 (Othertype 2)
  - Marriages (Bound), Aug. 1958-May 26, 1963 (Othertype 3)
  - Marriages, May 30, 1963-Aug. 30, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Marriages, Aug. 30, 1964-Feb. 26, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Marriages, Mar. 5, 1966-Aug. 26, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Marriages, Aug. 27, 1967-Sept. 7, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Marriages, Sept. 7, 1968-July 26, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Marriages, Aug. 2, 1969-Aug. 29, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marriages, Aug. 29, 1970-Sept. 11, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Marriages, Sept. 12, 1971-Feb. 8, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Marriages, Feb. 10, 1973-June 29, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Marriages, June 29, 1974-Sept. 20, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Marriages, Sept. 27, 1975-Feb. 12, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Baptisms, June 12, 1958-Sept. 23, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Baptisms, 1970-1973 (stubs from baptismal records) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Marriages, Sept. 27, 1986-Sept. 5, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Marriages, Sept. 5, 1987-Aug. 6, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Marriages, Aug. 6, 1988-June 24, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Marriages, Aug. 27, 1979-April 11, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Marriages, April 11, 1981-Aug. 8, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Marriages, Aug. 14, 1982-Sept. 17, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Marriages, Sept. 18, 1983-Oct. 21, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Marriages, Oct. 27, 1984-Oct. 19, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Marriages, Oct. 19, 1985-Sept. 27, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Marriages, June 24, 1989-July 10, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Marriages, July 11, 1993-Aug. 13, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Marriages, Aug. 13, 1994-Aug. 19, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Marriages, Aug. 19, 1995-Sept. 29, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Bibles, Hymnals, and Songbooks, 1883-1912
  - Original Stanford Memorial Church Pulpit Bible, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Apocrypha (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Century Company. In Excelsia, Hymns with Tunes for Christian Worship. New York: The Century Co, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Century Company. In Excelsia, Hymns with Tunes for Christian Worship. New York: The Century Co, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Century Company. In Excelsia, Hymns with Tunes for Christian Worship. New York: The Century Co, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Century Company. In Excelsia, Hymns with Tunes for Christian Worship. New York: The Century Co, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Book of Psalms (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Book of Psalms (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Book of Psalms (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Century Company. Hymns of Worship and Service. New York: The Century Co, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Century Company. Hymns of Worship and Service. New York: The Century Co, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Century Company. Hymns of Worship and Service. New York: The Century Co, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Biglow & Main. Gospel Hymns Consolidated. New York: Biglow & Main, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Episcopal Church. The Book of Common Prayer/The Hymnal. New York: James Pott & Co, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bible. New York: Hunt & Eaton, ca. 1902. [Original binding bore note "Stanford Memorial Chapel, 1902"; rebound in 1949 by Vernon Packer.] (Box 4)
  - Century Company. Hymns of Worship and Service; (College Edition). New York: The Century Co, 1912 [cover stamped "Leland Stanford Memorial Church Not to be Taken Away"] (Box 5)
  - Revised Holy Bible. New York: International Bible Agency, 1903. [cover stamped "Leland Stanford Memorial Church Not to be Taken Away"]
- Series VII: Publications about the Church
  - Press Releases (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, Newspapers, Magazines (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Newspapers, Magazines (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Daily series on religion, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series VIII: General Miscellany
  - Church Choir (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters and Promotional Letters (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Posters and Promotional Letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of Memorial Church (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 50th Anniversary of Memorial Church (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Thomas, and John Payne. Imitation of Christ translated from the Latin of Thomas A. Kemps. New Haven: Published by William Storer, 1822. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ussher, James. Sermons. London: Religious Tract Society, 1837. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Foster, Hannah Webster, and Abel Brown. The Coquette, or, The History of Eliza Wharton: A Novel Founded on Fact. Exeter: Published by Abel Brown, 1828. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Moran, Hugh. Typescript articles on history of Memorial Church (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorial Church Centennial, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Church Chimes (newsletter), 1916-1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Church Chimes (newsletter), 1923-1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Balaam's Ass (newsletter), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Balaam's Ass (newsletter), 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Balaam's Ass/Times & Eternity (newsletter), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Times & Eternity/Dynamis (newsletter), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Printing blocks used for illustrations in: Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church: the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. (Box 3)
  - Printing blocks used for illustrations in: Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church: the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. (Box 4)
  - Printing blocks used for illustrations in: Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church: the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. (Box 5)
  - Printing blocks used for illustrations in: Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church: the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. (Box 6)
  - Printing blocks used for illustrations in: Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church: the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. (Box 7)
- Series IX: Church Building
  - History (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reconstruction (includes correspondence with architects and stained glass artisans, etc.), 1907-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Survey of Decorations (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mosaics (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Inscriptions (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reconstruction of Mosaics (includes correspondence), 1910-1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church: the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. Palo Alto, Calif: Times Pub. Co, 1917. [45p. illus. inscribed by author] (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church: The Mosaic, the Windows, the Inscriptions. 1921. (1 copy)
  - Moulin, Gabriel. Stanford Memorial Church. San Francisco: Printed by H.L. Crocker Co, 1918. (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church, the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. Palo Alto, Calif: W.L. Hall, 1922. [64p. illus.] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church, the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. 3rd edition.Palo Alto, Calif: W.L. Hall, 1924. [64p. illus.]
  - Hall, Willis L. Stanford Memorial Church, the Mosaics, the Windows, the Inscriptions. 4th edition. Palo Alto: author, 1928. [64p. illus.] (2 copies)
  - Stanford Memorial Church. Stanford: Board of Trustees, 1946. [31p. illus.] (2 copies)
  - Stanford Memorial Church. Stanford: Board of Trustees, 1950. [31p. illus.] (1 copy)
  - Hall, Willis L. Four Notable Mosaics of Stanford Memorial Church in Color. Palo Alto, Cal: W.L. Hall, 1927. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Memorial Church. Stanford: Board of Trustees, 1954. [31p. illus.] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Memorial Church. Stanford: Board of Trustees, 1964. [31p. illus.]
  - Stanford Memorial Church. Stanford: Board of Trustees, 1968. [31p. illus.]
  - Stockholm, Gail, and Donald T. Carlson. Stanford Memorial Church: An Appreciative Guide for the Not-so-Casual Vistor. Stanford, Calif: Memorial Church and Office of Public Affairs, Stanford University, 1980. [86p. illus.] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University. Stanford Memorial Church. Stanford: Public Exercises. Sold by Student Guide Service. (3 copies) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Organ (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Rebuilding of Memorial Church," Campus Report insert, August 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - An Introduction to Stanford Memorial Church. Produced by Stanford Guide and Visitors Service, undated. (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Other visitor's guides
  - Description of the earthquake repair, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper articles on rebuilding (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reconstructing Memorial Church fundraising brochure, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Reports on stained glass window restoration (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Temko, Allan. "A Vision Restored," Stanford Magazine, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Thank-you certificates (blank), circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Taylor, Joseph, "An Inspiration in Italian Mosaic,", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chandeliers: drawings, photos, memos, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of Leslie Bone re restoration work, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stained glass condition analysis (report), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Structural Strengthening: Project Manual, phase one, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - OS roll: Tracings from mosaic angels repaired after 1989 quake
  - OS roll: Tracings from mosaic angels repaired after 1989 quake